# CATHERINE NGUYEN-CAT

Full-Stack Developer







100 Oldfield Road N16 OR J



https://www.linkedin.com/in/catherine-nguyen-cat

github.com/catanhtho019

#### **ABOUT ME**

I have 4 years experience in design and animation and I'm now a fullstack web developer combining my creative skillset and attention for detail. I have built and shipped user-ready Ruby on Rails web applications and completed Le Wagon London's coding bootcamp. Previously, I built a company website for Azure Designs using WordPress, which is limiting. So I decided to learn to code and make a career change that I am loving and want to continue with. I am looking to join an exciting company where I can continue to learn and challenge myself to improve amongst a great team.

# **WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS**

#### **Brunchees**

Web app to search and book for brunches in the desired area.

Built with Ruby, Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Heroku and ActiveRecord.

Working in a team I used Figma to draft a rough layout of the website.

built the front-end for index, show and profile page. I generated the search filter feature on index page, booking form and menu toggle on show page. Fixing front-end bugs. http://brunchee.rocks/

#### **My Venues**

Managing a team on Git and GitHub to build a web app for booking venues for events. Built with Ruby, Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Heroku and ActiveRecord. Building the front-end for home, index, show profile page. Fixing front-end bugs https://my-venues.herokuapp.com/

#### **Mister Cocktail**

Web app for adding and listing cocktail recipes.

Built with Ruby, Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Heroku, Ajax and ActiveRecord. My personal project building all back-end controllers and front-end design. https://cocktail-library.herokuapp.com/

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# ENGINE Group - July 2019 - Present | Web Developer

- Fixing bugs on client's website with HTML & CSS
- · Quality assessing webpages

# Humanscale - Aug 2018 - Feb 2019 | Marketing Assistant

- Produce external and internal marketing materials: newsletters, presentations, brochures, social media
- Updating content of company's English and international websites using CMS
- · Coordinating international event shows

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Full-Stack Web Developer**

Le Wagon Bootcamp, London Apr - Jun 2019

#### **BA Animation**

University of Westminster, Harrow 2011 - 2013

# Diploma Art & Design: Art & Architecture

Central Saint Martins, London 2010 - 2011

#### **SKILLS**

**HTML** 

CSS

JavaScript

Ruby

Ruby on Rails

SQL

PostgreSQL

Bootstrap

Git

GitHub

**MVC** Architecture

00P

Figma

Photoshop

Illustrator

After Effects

InDesign

#### **INTERESTS**

Dance
Musical Instruments
Drawing
Cooking
Travelling
Gaming

### Rainbow Designs Ltd. - April - May 2018 | Freelance Photographer/ Retoucher

- Managing CMS, addressing photo issues
- Photographing and retouching new products for the re-launch of ecommerce website. https://www.rainbowdesigns.co.uk

# Azure Designs International Ltd. - Jan 2016 - Aug 2018 | Designer

- Produce CAD designs of luggage and marketing materials: brochures, business cards and POS artwork for TK Maxx, Wilko and other retailers
- Designing layout and uploading content for the company's website on WordPress
- Photographing and retouching all incoming samples for archive and e-commerce.
- Quality Assess product samples

#### Jocelyn Burton Ltd. - Nov 2015- Aug 2017 | Design Assistant/Photographer

- Supervising team on photographing products and retouching volumes of images for website re-launch of Jocelyn Burton website.
- Managing marketing materials and communications to launch of a new line of jewellery for Sunny Art gallery exhibition
- Collaborating with Juan Pablo Molyneux on new conceptual illustrations of bespoke lamps and designing a series of bespoke zodiac animal goblets.